<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-13T18:18:33+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">CHIEN LAB</title><subtitle>Our group&apos;s research focuses on integrated circuits and their convergence with bio- and quantum technologies. We are dedicated to creating sensors and devices for point-of-care diagnostics and emphasizing continuous monitoring through wearables, implantable devices, injectables, and swallowables. Additionally, we explore millimeter-wave ICs for communication, sensing, and interfaces for qubits. Please come talk to us if you’re interested in!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Seminar at NYCU</title><link href="/2025/06/17/SSCS.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar at NYCU" /><published>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/06/17/SSCS</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/06/17/SSCS.html"><![CDATA[<p>Jun-Chau will be giving a seminar talk for SSCS at National Yung-Ming Chiao-Tung University on “CMOS-enabled biosensing for precision medicine and health”.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jun-Chau Chien</name></author><category term="Seminar" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jun-Chau will be giving a seminar talk for SSCS at National Yung-Ming Chiao-Tung University on “CMOS-enabled biosensing for precision medicine and health”.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seminar at NTU</title><link href="/2025/06/13/NTU_seminar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seminar at NTU" /><published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/06/13/NTU_seminar</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/06/13/NTU_seminar.html"><![CDATA[<p>Jun-Chau will be back to NTU and give a seminar talk on “Semiconductor-based Biotechnology” on June 13th to the NTU undergraduate students!</p>]]></content><author><name>Jun-Chau Chien</name></author><category term="Seminar" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jun-Chau will be back to NTU and give a seminar talk on “Semiconductor-based Biotechnology” on June 13th to the NTU undergraduate students!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Workshop presentation at VLSI Symposium 2025</title><link href="/2025/06/08/vlsi25workshop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workshop presentation at VLSI Symposium 2025" /><published>2025-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/06/08/vlsi25workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/06/08/vlsi25workshop.html"><![CDATA[<p>Jun-Chau will be presenting at the VLSI workshop: Recent Advances in CMOS Cellular and Molecular Biosensors. Please see program here: https://www.vlsisymposium.org/workshop/workshop2025_6/.</p>

<p>Title: Continuous Monitoring of Small Molecules Using Electrochemical Aptamer-Based Biosensors with CMOS Electronic
Abstract: The ability to continuously monitor specific molecules over extended periods can provide fundamentally new insights into disease dynamics and the transition from a healthy to a diseased state. This capability can also drive the development of next-generation screening and detection tools. However, only a few biomolecules—such as glucose, oxygen, and dopamine—can currently be monitored in real time due to multiple limitations in existing biosensor technologies. In this presentation, we introduce a class of biosensors known as aptamers. Aptamers are synthetic antibodies composed of nucleic acids (e.g., DNA or RNA) that can specifically bind to target analytes in complex samples, including whole blood. Importantly, they can be engineered into aptamer switches, which undergo reversible structural changes upon target binding. By conjugating electroactive reporters to these aptamers, structural changes—correlated to analyte concentration—can be detected electrochemically. Because aptamer switches do not require sample preparation, they are well-suited for continuous in vivo monitoring of biomolecules. However, integrating these structure-switching aptamers with readout electronics presents unique challenges. We will first outline the biosensor requirements and present our circuit innovations to meet them. This will be followed by discussion on system-level integration with wireless capabilities tailored for wearable and implantable applications. We will also address challenges such as signal drift and biofouling. Finally, we will demonstrate successful continuous monitoring of small-molecule drugs, such as antibiotics and chemotherapeutics, in freely moving rodents.</p>]]></content><author><name>Jun-Chau Chien</name></author><category term="Workshop" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jun-Chau will be presenting at the VLSI workshop: Recent Advances in CMOS Cellular and Molecular Biosensors. Please see program here: https://www.vlsisymposium.org/workshop/workshop2025_6/.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE SSC-L paper acceptance!</title><link href="/2025/06/01/SSCLpaper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE SSC-L paper acceptance!" /><published>2025-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/06/01/SSCLpaper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/06/01/SSCLpaper.html"><![CDATA[<p>Wei-Yu’s paper has been accepted to IEEE Solid-State Circuits Letter! Congrats! Paper title: “A Millimeter-Wave Standing-Wave Oscillator With Frequency-Specific Wave-Velocity Control Demonstrating Class-F Effects”. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/11030857</p>]]></content><author><name>Wei-Yu Lin and Jun-Chau Chien</name></author><category term="Publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Wei-Yu’s paper has been accepted to IEEE Solid-State Circuits Letter! Congrats! Paper title: “A Millimeter-Wave Standing-Wave Oscillator With Frequency-Specific Wave-Velocity Control Demonstrating Class-F Effects”. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/11030857]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nature Biomedical Engineering paper acceptance!</title><link href="/2025/05/24/NatureBME.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nature Biomedical Engineering paper acceptance!" /><published>2025-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/05/24/NatureBME</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/05/24/NatureBME.html"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations to Dr. Yihang Chen on his paper publication in Nature Biomedical Engineering! Paper title: “A biochemical sensor with continuous extended stabiity in vivo”. Paper link: https://www.nature.com/articles/s41551-025-01389-6.</p>

<p>The team demonstrates stable aptamer sensor operation for weeks with smart surface engineering! This is a very challenging reserach topic, congratulations, Yihang!</p>]]></content><author><name>Yihang Chen, Prof. H. Tom Soh @ Stanford University</name></author><category term="Publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations to Dr. Yihang Chen on his paper publication in Nature Biomedical Engineering! Paper title: “A biochemical sensor with continuous extended stabiity in vivo”. Paper link: https://www.nature.com/articles/s41551-025-01389-6.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CLEO paper acceptance!</title><link href="/2025/05/09/CLEOpaper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CLEO paper acceptance!" /><published>2025-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/05/09/CLEOpaper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/05/09/CLEOpaper.html"><![CDATA[<p>Congrats to the NSF-Fuse team with two paper acceptance to CELO! Information below:</p>
<ol>
  <li>High-Efficiency mmWave-to-Optical Converter with &gt;30dB Sideband SNR on a Monolithic Integration Platform
Xinchang Zhang; Manuj Singh; Hyeong Seok Oh; Awani Khodkumbhe; Ruocheng Wang; Ruifu Li; Deniz Onural; Vladimir Stojanovic; Danijela Cabric; Ali Niknejad; Jun-Chau Chien; Miloš A. Popović</li>
  <li>Efficient wideband mmWave-to-optical signal transduction by a monolithic CMOS LNA and photonic molecule modulator
Xinchang Zhang; Hyeong Seok Oh; Manuj Singh; Ruocheng Wang; Awani Khodkumbhe; Ruifu Li; Vladimir Stojanovic; Danijela Cabric; Ali M. Niknejad; Jun-Chau Chien; Miloš A. Popović</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name>Hyeong Seok Oh and Jun-Chau Chien</name></author><category term="Publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congrats to the NSF-Fuse team with two paper acceptance to CELO! Information below: High-Efficiency mmWave-to-Optical Converter with &gt;30dB Sideband SNR on a Monolithic Integration Platform Xinchang Zhang; Manuj Singh; Hyeong Seok Oh; Awani Khodkumbhe; Ruocheng Wang; Ruifu Li; Deniz Onural; Vladimir Stojanovic; Danijela Cabric; Ali Niknejad; Jun-Chau Chien; Miloš A. Popović Efficient wideband mmWave-to-optical signal transduction by a monolithic CMOS LNA and photonic molecule modulator Xinchang Zhang; Hyeong Seok Oh; Manuj Singh; Ruocheng Wang; Awani Khodkumbhe; Ruifu Li; Vladimir Stojanovic; Danijela Cabric; Ali M. Niknejad; Jun-Chau Chien; Miloš A. Popović]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IEEE MWTL paper acceptance!</title><link href="/2025/05/05/MWTLpaper.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IEEE MWTL paper acceptance!" /><published>2025-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/05/05/MWTLpaper</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/05/05/MWTLpaper.html"><![CDATA[<p>Congrats to the team on paper acceptance to IEEE MWTL 2025! Paper title: “Experimental Studies of Millimeter-Wave CMOS LO Circuits for High-temperature Qubits Operations.”</p>]]></content><author><name>Yi-Ting Chen, Guan-Yu Haung, Prof. Jiun-Yun Li (NTU), and Ming-Jui Lin (NTU)</name></author><category term="Publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congrats to the team on paper acceptance to IEEE MWTL 2025! Paper title: “Experimental Studies of Millimeter-Wave CMOS LO Circuits for High-temperature Qubits Operations.”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EECS Department Arthur M. Hopkin Award</title><link href="/2025/04/19/AlexAward.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EECS Department Arthur M. Hopkin Award" /><published>2025-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/04/19/AlexAward</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/04/19/AlexAward.html"><![CDATA[<p>Alex received the Berkeley EECS Department Arthur M. Hopkin Award for oustanding undergraduate researchers! Congratulations!</p>]]></content><author><name>Alexander Di</name></author><category term="Award" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alex received the Berkeley EECS Department Arthur M. Hopkin Award for oustanding undergraduate researchers! Congratulations!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">RFIC25 Student Paper Finalist</title><link href="/2025/04/11/RFIC25finalist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="RFIC25 Student Paper Finalist" /><published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/04/11/RFIC25finalist</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/04/11/RFIC25finalist.html"><![CDATA[<p>Ying-Han’s RFIC’25 paper on clock distribution has been selected for student paper finalist! Good job and best of luck!</p>]]></content><author><name>Ying-Han You</name></author><category term="Publication" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ying-Han’s RFIC’25 paper on clock distribution has been selected for student paper finalist! Good job and best of luck!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Berkeley Fellowship</title><link href="/2025/04/01/AlexDi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Berkeley Fellowship" /><published>2025-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-13T18:17:46+00:00</updated><id>/2025/04/01/AlexDi</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/04/01/AlexDi.html"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations our incoming PhD student Alex on receiving the Berkeley Fellowship!</p>]]></content><author><name>Alexander Di</name></author><category term="Fellowship" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations our incoming PhD student Alex on receiving the Berkeley Fellowship!]]></summary></entry></feed>